doctorshealthpress.com 2019-03-08

# Our Privacy Policy & Terms of Use

**Privacy Policy**

We at Doctors Health Press have a strict anti-spam, anti-spyware, and anti-adware policy. Your privacy is important to us! We realize how important your privacy is to you, and that is why we will never sell your e-mail address.

Some sections of this web site may require you to submit information in order for you to benefit from the specified features (such as the free Doctors Health Press e-Bulletin subscriptions, health tips, order processing, etc.) or to participate in a particular activity (such as a contest or other sales promotions). Your e-mail address may be added to our Doctors Health Press e-Bulletin subscription.

When you subscribe to the Doctors Health Press e-Bulletin, we will send you a welcome e-mail introducing you to the Doctors Health Press e-Bulletin. Subscribers will occasionally receive information on health topics, products, services, and special deals. We may enter into marketing relationships or joint ventures with third-party advertisers or other companies that provide products or services that we believe may be of interest to Doctors Health Press e-Bulletin subscribers. They may periodically send information to newsletter subscribers.

**Information Collection:**

We may gather general information about our web site users and their usage of the web site. This information includes IP address, pages viewed, number of visitors, purchases made, etc. Cookies are used to help provide us with this information regarding the user interaction with the web site.

**1) Types of Information We Collect:**

We collect personal information from you and any devices (including mobile devices) you use when you purchase products, subscribe to the e-mail list, or use our services. Some of this personal information, such as a way to identify you, is necessary to complete orders or provide requested information. The provision of all other personal information is voluntary, but may be necessary in order to use our services.

Examples of ways in which we may collect such information from you include the following:

Registration and ordering: Before ordering products through our site, you must complete a registration form and/or create an account. This will require you to provide certain personal information, including, but not limited to, your name, shipping and billing addresses, phone number, e-mail address, and payment information. In addition, you may also be asked to provide your country of residence so we can comply with applicable laws and regulations. These kinds of personal information are used for billing purposes, to fulfill your orders, to communicate with you about your order and this site, and for internal or third-party marketing and promotional purposes. If we encounter a problem when processing your order, we will use the personal information to contact you.

E-mail address: Some areas of the site allow you to enter your e-mail address for purposes including, but not limited to, registering for the Doctors Health Press newsletter, promotional e-mails, and e-mails from approved partners. You may unsubscribe at any time from these messages by clicking on the “Unsubscribe” link contained in any promotional e-mail. (Please note that despite unsubscribing from such marketing communications, we may still contact you in relation to your order(s) or any issues relating to any business you conduct with us.) 

Additional details on the information we collect: 

1.1 We collect general types of information about you when you visit and use our web site; examples include personal information, demographic information, behavioral information, and indirect information. Sometimes we collect combinations of these types of information.

1.2 “Personal information” is information that can be used to identify you or any other individual to whom the information may relate. This is information that you are prompted to provide to us. Such information may include your name, address, telephone number(s), mobile number(s) and e-mail address, credit card number(s), bank account(s), or other unique information about you that you provide to us during the registration process, or though the course of communicating with us about the products and services provided on our web site. We may collect this same information about all other persons when you provide it to us. 

1.3 “Demographic information” is information that may or may not be unique to you in the sense that it refers to selected population characteristics. Such information may include, but is not limited to, zip code, mobile phone carrier, age, gender, salary range, education and marital status, occupation, industry of employment, and personal and online interests.

1.4 “Behavioral information” is information that is automatically collected pertaining to how you use our web site, the areas of our web site that you visit, what services you access, and information about your computer hardware and software, including your IP address, geographic location, browser preference, operating system type, domain names, times that you access the Internet, and other web sites you have visited.

1.5 “Third-party information” is information about you that we acquire from a third party that may include personal, demographic, behavioral, and indirect information. This collection may include, but is not limited to, first-party cookies, third-party cookies, anonymous cookies, persistent identifiers, e-mail opt-ins, and search engine keywords. We have no access to or control over these cookies and other tracking devices used by third-party advertisers and networks. We have no responsibility or liability for the policies and practices of these parties.

1.6 “Web technology information” is information we automatically collect from you when you visit our web site. This includes Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. This information is collected from the use of cookies, web beacons, or JavaScript.

1.7 No Information Collected from Children. We will never knowingly collect any Personal Information from children under the age of 13. If we obtain actual knowledge that we have collected Personal Information about a child under the age of 13, that information will be immediately deleted from its database. Because we do not collect such information, we have no such information to use or to disclose to third parties.

1.8 No Sensitive Health Information Collected. We do not collect information about past, present, or potential future medical conditions or treatments.

1.9 Credit Card Information and Bank Account Information. We may, in certain instances, collect credit card number(s), bank account information, and related information when you place an order on our web site. When the credit card or bank account information is submitted to us, such information is encrypted and is protected with SSL encryption software. We will use the credit card information or bank account information for purposes of processing and completing the transaction you requested. Such information will be disclosed to third parties as necessary to complete the requested purchase transaction.

**2) Collection of Information Through Web Beacons**

2.1 Generally, we, as well as third-party vendors and supporting advertisers, use technologies such as cookies, web beacons, and JavaScript. These technologies collect Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. This information is used to analyze trends, administer our web site, track users’ movements through our web site, and gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on these technologies on an individual or aggregated basis.

2.2 Third-Party Cookies. We allow third-party vendors and advertisers to set their own cookies on and through our web site. We have no control over the practices of those third parties and are not responsible for their technology or tracking. We encourage you to review the policies of such persons or entities on their web sites. We use AdWords Remarketing through Google, which is a Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting service provided by Google LLC that connects the activity on our web site with the AdWords advertising network and the DoubleClick cookie. That cookie collects information regarding certain patterns in your browsing history. To opt-out of this tracking, please see <https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en>. We also participate in all of Google Analytics Advertising. This includes (i) Remarketing with Google Analytics; (ii) Google Display Network Impression Reporting; (iii) DoubleClick Campaign Manager Integration; and (iv) Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. Google uses cookies to track activity performed by Google Analytics and its AdWords or DoubleClick cookie. To opt out, please see <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>. We also use Google Analytics, which is an analysis service also provided by Google LLC. Google utilizes the data collected through its cookies to track and examine the use of this site, to prepare reports on its activities, and to share them with other Google services. You may opt-out of the Google Analytics service using Google’s Opt-out Browser Add-on available at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>.

2.3 Web Beacons. We use electronic images known as web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel gifs, clear gifs, or action tags), which allow us to collect information about your visit to our web site, measure and improve the effectiveness of advertisements, and track delivery of advertising. Web beacons collect only a limited set of information, including a cookie number, time and date of page view, as well as a description of the page on which the web beacon resides. We may also use web beacons in e-mail messages sent to you. This allows us to determine if you opened or acted upon the e-mail messages. Because web beacons are the same as any other content request, you cannot opt out of or refuse them. However, they can be rendered ineffective by either opting out of cookies or changing the cookie setup in your browser.

**3) Security**

We employ physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect the personal information you provide to us. We endeavor to safeguard and protect your information. When you submit information on our web site, such information is protected both online and offline. We have security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of personal information under our control. The servers in which we store your information are kept in a secure physical environment. The servers have industry-standard firewalls. Access to such servers is password protected and access by our employees is limited. Currently, we use Secure Socket Layer software (“SSL”) to protect data and to secure any transactions. SSL encrypts information including credit card number(s) and names and addresses as they are transmitted over the Internet. Please be advised that, although we take commercially reasonable technological precautions to protect your data, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure; therefore, we cannot and do not warrant that your information will be absolutely secure. Any transmission of data at or through our web site is at your own risk. However, access to your information is strictly limited and not accessible to the public.

**4) How We Use Information Collected**

4.1 How We Use Your Personal Information: 

We use the personal information we collect from you for a range of different business purposes and according to different legal bases of processing. The following is a summary of how and according to which legal bases we use your personal information.

We use your personal information to fulfill a contract with you and provide you with our services, to comply with our legal obligation, to protect your vital interest, or as may be required for the public good. This includes:

  * To provide payment processing and account management; operate, measure, and improve our services; keep our services safe, secure, and operational; and customize site content that includes items and services that you may like in response to actions that you take.
  * To contact you regarding your account, to troubleshoot problems with your account or order, to resolve a dispute, to collect fees or monies owed, or as otherwise necessary to provide you with customer service.
  * When contacting you for such purposes as outlined above, we may contact you via e-mail, telephone, SMS/text messages, postal mail, and via mobile push notifications.
  * To provide other services requested by you as described when we collect the information.
  * We use general location information to provide you with location-based services (such as advertising and other personalized content).
  * To prevent, detect, mitigate, and investigate fraud; security breaches; or other potentially prohibited or illegal activities.

We use your personal information to pursue our legitimate interests where your rights and freedoms do not outweigh these interests. We have implemented controls to balance our interests with your rights. This includes:

  * Contacting you via e-mail or postal mail in order to offer you coupons, discounts and special promotions, third-party offers, poll your opinions through surveys or questionnaires, and inform you about our services, as authorized by applicable law.
  * Delivering targeted marketing, service updates, and promotional offers based on your communication preferences.
  * Measuring the performance of our e-mail marketing campaigns (e.g. by analyzing open and click rates).
  * Monitoring and improving the information security of our site.

With your consent, we may use your personal information to:

  * Provide you with marketing via telephone calls, e-mail, or SMS/text messages.
  * Provide you with marketing from third parties.
  * Customize third-party advertising you might see on third-party web sites.

**You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time.**

We will not make automated decisions about you that would significantly affect you, unless such a decision is necessary as part of a contract we have with you, we have your consent, or we are required by law to use such technology.

4.2 Ways You Can Access, Control, and Correct Your Personal Information:

You can see, review, and change most of your personal information by requesting it by contacting the Privacy Officer below. Please update your personal information immediately if it changes or is inaccurate. 

We will honor any statutory right you might have to access, modify, or erase your personal information. To request access and to find out whether any fees may apply, if permitted by applicable national laws, please contact us using the information below. Where you have a statutory right to request access to or request the modification or erasure of your personal information, we can still withhold that access or decline to modify or erase your personal information in some cases, in accordance with applicable national laws.

If you request that we stop processing some or all of your personal information or you withdraw (where applicable) your consent for our use or disclosure of your personal information for purposes set out in this privacy notice, we might not be able to provide you with all of the services and customer support offered and authorized under this privacy notice and our Terms of Use.

Upon your request, we will remove your personal information from view as soon as reasonably possible, based on your account activity and in accordance with applicable national laws.

4.3 How Long We Keep Your Personal Information:

We retain personal information regarding you or your use of our services for as long as your account is subscribed to our services or for as long as needed to provide you with our services and warranties. We also retain personal information for as long as necessary to achieve the purposes described in this Privacy Policy—for example, to comply with our legal obligations, to protect us in the event of disputes, and to enforce our agreements and to protect our and others’ interests. 

The precise periods for which we keep your personal information vary depending on the nature of the information and why we need it. Factors we consider in determining these periods include the minimum required retention period prescribed by law or recommended as best practice, contractual agreements, warranties, the period during which a claim can be made with respect to an agreement or other matter, whether the personal information has been aggregated or pseudonymized, and other relevant criteria. For example, the period we keep your e-mail address is connected to how long your e-mail is subscribed to our mailing list. 

After it is no longer necessary for us to retain your personal information, we will dispose of it in a secure manner, according to our data retention and deletion policies.

You may delete your personal information by contacting us at privacyofficer@doctorshealthpress.com and we will delete the personal information we hold about you (unless we need to retain it for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy).

Please note that in the course of providing our services, we collect and maintain aggregated, anonymized, or de-personalized information, which we may retain indefinitely.

**5) Disclosure of Information to Others**

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this Privacy Policy. 

5.1 Providing Services and Products. We use the information we gather on our web site to provide you with the services and/or products you have requested. This may include passing your information on to a third party to provide such services or products. Although our contractual arrangement limits how this party can use your information, we do not control the privacy practices of third parties. If you have any questions or wish to remove your information from the third-party databases, you will need to contact that party directly.

5.2 Improving Our Web Site. We use the information we gather to respond to any inquiries you make, operate and improve the functionality of our web site, and deliver the products and services advertised on our web site. Our services include the display of personalized products, content, and advertising relating to your experience and interests. 

**Service Providers and Financial Institutions Partners as Follows:**

Third-party service providers who help us to provide our services; payment processing services; assist us in providing customized advertising; and assist us with the prevention, detection, mitigation, and investigation of potentially illegal acts, violations of our Terms of Use, and fraud and/or security breaches.

Third-party shipping providers (e.g., DHL, UPS, USPS, Canada Post, etc.) with whom we share delivery address information, contact information, and shipment tracking information for the purposes of facilitating the delivery of items purchased and other delivery-related communications.

**Law Enforcement, Legal Proceedings, and as Authorized by Law:**

To law enforcement or governmental agencies, or authorized third-parties, in response to a verified request or legal process relating to a criminal investigation or alleged or suspected illegal activity or any other activity that exposes us, you, or any other of our users to legal liability. We will only disclose information we deem relevant to the investigation or inquiry, such as name, city, state/province, zip/postal code, telephone number, e-mail address, IP address, and purchase history.

To third parties involved in a legal proceeding, if they provide us with a subpoena, court order, or substantially similar legal basis, or we otherwise believe in good faith that the disclosure of information is necessary to prevent imminent physical harm or financial loss or to report suspected illegal activity.

**Change of Ownership:**

In the unlikely event that our company or substantially all of our assets are acquired by a third party, customer information may be one of the transferred assets. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to try to require that the transferee use personal information provided through the services in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy. 

**Mail Solicitation:**

We may also provide your name, customer history, and mailing address to third parties, such as service providers, contractors, and third-party publishers and advertisers, for a variety of purposes unless you choose to opt out by mailing [customersupport@doctorshealthpress.com](mailto:customersupport@doctorshealthpress.com) stating you wish to be removed from third-party direct mailing offers, along with your name and mailing address.

**CASL Disclosure:**

To assist in compliance with Canadian Anti-Spam Legislation (CASL), select information and data relating to the opt-in process to the online newsletter is recorded. This may include, but is not limited to, the point of sign-up, time, date, IP address, and e-mail address. This information is linked to the associated e-mail account for the purpose of demonstrating express consent.

(i) Product and Service Delivery. We share your information with third parties who help us in the delivery of the products and services you have requested.

(ii) Web Site Functionality. We share your information with companies and individuals we employ to perform technical functions on our behalf. Examples include third parties who host our web site, analyze our data, provide marketing assistance, process credit card payments, and provide customer service.

(iii) Anonymous Information. We share aggregated anonymous information about you, combined with other persons using our web site, with third parties so that they can understand the kinds of visitors that come to our web site and how those visitors use our web site. This includes demographic information and behavioral information.

(iv) Legal Process. We disclose your information if legally required to do so, or at our discretion, pursuant to a request from a governmental entity, or if we believe in good faith that such action is necessary to (a) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process; (b) protect our rights or property, or our affiliated companies; (c) prevent a crime or protect national security; or (d) protect the personal safety of users or the public.

(v) Acquisition or Merger. We may disclose and transfer your information to a third party who acquires any or all of our business, whether such acquisition is by way of merger, consolidation, or purchase of all or a substantial portion of our assets. In the event we become the subject of an insolvency proceeding, whether voluntary or involuntary, we or our liquidator, administrator, receiver, or administrative receiver may sell, license, or otherwise dispose of such information in a transaction approved by the court.

**6) Changes to Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to make material changes to the substance of this Privacy Policy. We will post those changes through a prominent notice on the web site, so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and to whom we will disclose it.

**7) Your California Rights**

7.1 California residents have the right to receive, once a year, information about third parties with whom we have shared information about you or your family for their marketing purposes during the previous calendar year, and a description of the categories of personal information shared. In addition, California residents have the right to know if we respond to “do not track” signals or cookies. We do not respond to such signals or cookies.

7.2 As stated in this Policy, you have agreed to allow us to share information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes until you remove your information; and thus, you have agreed to this disclosure. California customers may request further information about our compliance with this law by sending us an e-mail at [privacyofficer@doctorshealthpress.com](mailto:privacyofficer@doctorshealthpress.com). Please note that we are only required to respond to one request per customer each year, and we are not required to respond to requests made by means other than through this e-mail address.

**Data Transfers:**

Personal information that you submit through our services may be transferred to countries other than where you live, such as, for example, to our servers in North America. 

Your personal information may be transferred to countries that do not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information.

**Purchase Information:**

If you have previously purchased goods or services from us, we may provide to you details of similar goods or services, or other goods and services that you may be interested in.

Please note you can remove yourself from our e-mail list at any time. We supply a link at the bottom of each e-mail to manage your subscription to the Doctors Health Press e-Bulletin. Additionally, to unsubscribe, simply send an e-mail to [customerservice@doctorshealthpress.com](mailto:customerservice@doctorshealthpress.com) with the word “unsubscribe” in the subject line.

**Surveys and Contests:**

Periodically, we will send out requests for information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and appreciated. The user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address) and demographic information (such as zip/postal code, gender, and age information). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site and additional Doctors Health Press educational, editorial, and marketing materials.

**Third-Party Links/Ads:**

On occasion, we will feature links or ads to third parties on this web site. Though we provide links, it does not mean that we endorse or approve of that site’s content or policy towards visitor privacy. You should review their privacy policy before sending them any personal data.

**Disclosure of Information:**

We may disclose necessary personal information to third parties or service providers that help us provide services to you or deliver products to you. For example, we will disclose your billing information to payment processors for the purpose of processing the transaction. Also, we will disclose your shipping address to fulfilment and shipping contractors to deliver a product to you.

**Electronic Consent**

These terms and conditions apply to all transactions made on or through this web site. This Agreement is intended to be governed by the Electronic Signatures in Global and National Commerce Act. You manifest your agreement to the terms and conditions in this document by any act demonstrating your assent thereto, including clicking the submit button for the order, or by merely accessing the web site, whether you have read these terms or not. This includes your authorization to charge your credit card or debit your bank account. Please print these terms and conditions for your personal records.

In addition, you consent to receiving electronic communications from Doctors Health Press Inc. relating to your account. You agree that any notices, agreements, disclosures, or other communications that we send to you electronically will satisfy any legal communication requirements, including that such communications be in writing. You should maintain copies of electronic communications by printing a paper copy or saving an electronic copy. You also consent to receiving certain other communications from us, such as newsletter special offers, promotional announcements, and customer surveys via e-mail or other methods.

By placing an order with us, you will be deemed to have read, understood, and agreed to these Terms and Conditions of Use (collectively, “Terms”). If you do not agree to be bound by these Terms, you may not access or use the web site, or purchase any products through the web site. By accessing, using, or ordering products through the web site, you affirm that you have read this Agreement and understand, agree, and consent to all Terms contained herein.

**Contacting Us:**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact Doctors Health Press’ Privacy Officer by e-mail or postal mail as follows:

**email:** [privacy@doctorshealthpress.com](mailto:privacy@doctorshealthpress.com)  
**mail:** Doctors Health Press – Privacy Officer  

The Privacy Officer should be contacted with complaints or inquiries regarding the Privacy Policy or information management procedures.

Simply send a message via mail or e-mail, identifying yourself, your concern or question, and appropriate contact information to respond to your inquiry. Additional information may be requested to assist us in identifying you and/or authenticating you on our systems.

Personal information collected is used to fulfill orders and provide services to users and customers. Disclosures to third parties include the information required to process or fulfill orders, provide information and mailings regarding products or services you may be interested in, or complete a transaction, unless otherwise required by law. If a customer or individual wishes to view the personal information collected in their profile, requests should also be made to the Privacy Officer. All reasonable attempts will be made to respond within 30 days.

Please note that we update this Privacy Policy from time to time. Please review this policy regularly.

You may have the right to restrict or object to the processing of your personal information, or to exercise a right to data portability under applicable law. You also may have the right to lodge a complaint with a competent supervisory authority, subject to applicable law. If you are subject to EU data protection laws, we suggest you lodge any such complaints with our lead supervisory authority:

Irish Data Protection Commissioner  
Office of the Data Protection Commissioner  
Canal House, Station Road, Portarlington, Co. Laois, R32 AP23, Ireland  
Phone +353 57 868 4757  
Fax: +353 57 868 4757  
E-mail: [info@dataprotection.ie](mailto:info@dataprotection.ie)
